你保证喜欢我送的礼物吗
You promise you like your gift?
《我们的生活》前情提要
Previously, on This Is Us...
这条毛巾吗  简直糟透了
The towel? It's absolutely terrible.
字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
据说要从上面抱着
He said you just go up and over
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
最新最快海外影视字幕下载
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
然后包起来
and burrito him.
他们一转眼就上大学了
They'll be in college soon.
■
翻译:  青椒  小泡椒  小尼克  小应子
公主陛下
Your Highness.
我来给你找个皇冠
Need to find you a crown.
翻译:  桑葚  吸吸粒呀  劫数Bobby猫
我们在一起相处也特别愉快
We're pretty good together.
校对:  劫数Bobby猫  红枫
洛杉矶的演员们来到这里
These L.A. actors, they come out here, right?
来剧院里随便演几个小角色
They do their little stint in theater
只为满足自己的虚荣心
just to feel better about themselves.
时间轴:  格瑞特  ccisoda
我来这是有正当理由的
I'm here for the right reasons.
赶紧把这戏对完吧  可以吗
Let's get this over with, shall we?
-角色给你了  -你说什么
- You got the part. - Wait, I'm sorry. What?
他们觉得"保姆"来演会热卖
They think the nanny will sell tickets.
后期:  宝宝  精校&总监:  红枫Gabriel
我一直都对不起你
I did everything wrong by you,
而你每件事都做得很对
and you've done everything right.
凯文来了
Look. It's Kevin.
这是我生父
This is my biological father.
这事得跟我好好聊聊啊
Wow. Well, that probably is gonna be a longer conversation,
但很高兴认识你
but it's good to meet you.
幸会
It's a pleasure to meet you.
一记长传
Long signal pass.
保迪莫破开八人联防
Baltimore hopping out of an eight man front.
纳马斯远投
Namath throwing deep.
接到了  萨奥迅速跑开接到了球
Sauer, gets wide, get it, he was there.
通过假晃运球甩开兰尼·迈尔斯...
He had an inside step on Lenny Miles...
啤酒呢
Beer.
妈妈
Mommy.
丽贝卡  你别跟妹妹在这儿玩了
Rebecca, you and your sister need to play somewhere else.
爸爸要看球
Your father's trying to watch the game.
里克·沃克  21号球员
Rick Volk, number 21,
假动作运球
uh, coming with a fake
加快速度欺身而上
safety blitz and he goes up top.
这招玩得非常漂亮...
So that, um, is in pretty good...
他虽然不像洛奇·比尔或者弗兰克·哈里斯
He doesn't get all the glory of Rocky Bleier
那么功成名就  但他非常优秀...
or Franco Harris, but he's been a great...
杰克
Jack.
Jack!
在
Yeah. ‭
抱歉
Sorry.
我不要像我妈妈一样
No. I refuse to be my mother
她盯着我爸  而我爸盯着电视
staring at my father as he stares at the television.
好
Okay.
辛辛那提似乎有些疲惫...
I think Cincinnati's looked a little tired...
你教我吧
So teach me.
传授下橄榄球的知识
Teach me football.
有攻击线
We got an offensive line...
还有防守线  以及...
defensive line. Quart...
-两边是得分区  -没错  还有四分卫
- End zone, end zone. - End zone, quarterback...
布拉德肖就在正后方
There's Bradshaw straight back...
太逊了啊  布拉德肖
You suck, Bradshaw!
-什么水平  -宝贝
- Come on, man. ‭- Babe...
他拿过三次超级碗冠军
The man has three Super Bowl rings.
-别太着急  -可他居然
- Give him a break. - Yeah, he also
让弗兰科如入无人之地
had Franco wide open in the flat.
你会不会防守  布拉德肖
You're a freakin' bum, Bradshaw.
会不会防守
You're a freakin' bum.
他总这样
Typical Bradshaw.
超级碗
Super Bowl!
-该上路啦  -这么快
- Time to tailgate! ‭- Oh, already?
没错  我得走了  青蛙酒吧要开赛前派对
Yeah, babe. I got to move. Froggy's wants me to sing
请我过去唱歌
at their pre-game party.
-周日的超级碗比赛吗  -对
- Super Bowl Sunday? ‭- Yeah.
一年中就今天人最多
Biggest crowd of the whole year.
-而且我们可以免费喝  -太好了
- And we get to drink for free. - Oh, yeah.
你记得早点去
So be there early, okay?
布拉德肖那老家伙还没开始热身
I'll be there before Bradshaw even begins
我就已经到场了
warming up his old noodle arm.
别这么说他  宝贝
Easy on Bradshaw, babe.
在我家不许这样
Not in this house.
真是我家宝
That's my girl. ‭
米格尔和雪莉能去吗
Are Miguel and Shelly gonna make it?
能  他们说到时候见
Yeah. They're gonna meet us there, you know,
不过要看他们能不能找到保姆
depending on if they can get a babysitter,
而且不能跟上次一样
and one that doesn't show up completely
找个嗑得神志不清的瘾君子
stoned out of her gourd this time.
到底为什么要生孩子
Why do people have kids?
不是很懂
No idea.
好吧
All right.
你还好吗
You okay?
住手
Stop.
兰德尔  醒醒
Randall, wake the hell up.
你都把化疗药放进你的奶昔里了
You almost put a chemo pill in your shake.
凯文大伯
Uncle Kevin,
你为什么在书上乱写乱画
why are you writing in your book?
小宝贝  这是剧本
Play, sweetheart. It's a play,
导演希望我能做点场景表演
and the director wants me doing scene work.
可你似乎一直在写
You seem to be doing a lot of writing.
因为太多人告诉我该怎么做了  威廉
Well, I seem to be getting a lot of direction, William.
其实  你的声音很不错
Tell you what. You got a great voice.
有没有试过配音
You ever do any voice-over work?
应该试试
Well, you should.
真的  你可以去演...
Really. I mean, you could be a...
比如动画影片里的猫头鹰
like a... like a... like an owl in a Pixar movie,
-对吧  -开玩笑
- right? ‭- Yeah.
-无意冒犯  -这有什么冒犯的
- No offense. - Not sure why I would take offense to that.
我不吃蓝莓
Oh, I don't do blueberries.
-我也不吃  -你啥时候开始不吃了
- Me neither. - Since when?
-今天开始  -是吧
- Since now. - Yeah.
都不说味道如何
It's not the taste, right?
蓝莓皮那个口感  太恶心了
It's the texture of the skin, it's gross.
我也不想吃蓝莓了
Yeah. I don't want blueberries either.
好的没问题  请问还有没有其他忌口
Yeah. Understood. Uh, any other dietary restrictions
我跟厨房的人说一下
I should let the staff know about?
算了  你那么忙
No, man. You're busy. I'll just, you know,
回头我有空给你列个单子吧
I'll make a list for you later when I get some time.
谢了
Thanks, buddy.
你得先吃点东西垫垫胃  威廉
You need to put something in your stomach, William.
吐司  药片和果汁  按这顺序来  好吗
Toast, pills, juice. That's the order. Okay?
你是在吃药吗
Is that medicine?
你是不是感冒了  爷爷
Do you have a cold, Grandpa?
-爷爷没事  -只是维生素
- Grandpa's fine. - No. They're just vitamins.
这么说
So.
她俩知道他是爷爷
You, uh, told the girls that he's Grandpa,
但不知道他病了  对吗
but not that he's sick. Right?
这样很冒险
That's ballsy.
凯文
Hey, so, Kevin, uh,
自从那天你过来
it's been a few days now, you know,
-就一直住在这里  -也没提前打电话
- since you showed up. - Without calling.
-对  -见到你我们很开心
- Right. - And... and it's great to see you.
就是想问下...
I was just sort of wondering...
怎么问比较礼貌呢
How do I say this politely?
你什么时候走
When are you leaving?
对  就这意思
Yeah. Yeah.
这个啊
Yeah.
我  我  这个 我随时...
No, I mean, come on. I can, I... I can, um...
我随时可以走  就是...
I can get out of here whenever. I just... I...
我想着顺便可以来陪陪你们
I saw this as an opportunity to hang with you two,
还有俩小宝贝  不过...
you know, and the girls, but, uh...
其实说实话  这个剧本
Plus I... honestly, this play, guys,
让我有点头疼
it's kicking my ass a little, You know? ‭
而且一个人住酒店太孤独了
And it's so lonely at that hotel.
我一个人住个大套间
I mean, I got this big suite all to myself,
但是房间越大  就越寂寞
but I guess the bigger the hotel room, the emptier it can feel.
我就坐在那儿
You know? I'm sitting there.
虽然那里有八百针的高质量床单
I got that 800 thread count sheets.
迷你冰箱里也有吃不完的小吃
I got the endless minibar snacks.
还有高级的燕麦香皂和长毛绒睡袍
You got the fancy oatmeal soaps, plush robes
而我就只坐在那儿
and all I can do is sit there
默默地想着
and think about how...
太安静了
quiet it is.
-我们要了  -什么
- We'll take it. - What's that?
酒店  我和贝丝  我们今晚就去住
The hotel. Beth and I, we'll take it, tonight.
不  兰德尔  我们临时去哪找保姆呢
No, Randall. Where are we gonna get a sitter?
不  我们有两位家人
No, We got two family members
-不不不  -免费住在咱们家
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no. - living in our house for free.
有一个还在电视上演过保姆
One of them played a nanny on TV.
不不  实际上是换工住宿生
No. ‭No, actually, an au pair.
准确的说  我在电视上演的是个换工住宿生
Technically, I played an au pair on TV.
这两者是有区别的  很多人都不知道
There's a difference. A lot of people don't know that.
我饰演的是一个换工住宿生
I was... an au pair.
他们本想管这剧叫什么《换工住宿生》  但...
They were gonna call the show what Au Pair, but the...
叫"保姆"效果更好  我可以照顾孩子们
Manny tested better. I-I can watch the girls.
-我去收拾行李  -好
- I'm-a go pack. ‭- Okay.
我现在去收拾行李
I'm-a go pack right now.
早安
Good morning.
在床上吃早餐
Breakfast in bed?
是的
Yeah.
我做了什么能享受这种待遇呢
What did I do to deserve this?
说不好啊
I don't know.
你为我做了太多贴心的事
You've done a lot of really nice things for me,
所以我想回报你
so I wanted to return the favor.
把"硬纸板"切成方块  放到碗里
Oh. By cutting up cardboard into little squares
来回报我吗
and putting it in a bowl?
这些是奶酪块
Those are cheese squares.
"美味啊"
Oh, yum.
上面是什么
Yeah. What's on top?
大麻籽
Oh, hemp seed.
大麻籽洒在上面
Hemp seeds on top?
你可真会避重就轻
Boy, you really buried the lede.
我要吃啦
‭Now I'm in.
怎么了  你不要吃点什么黑暗料理吗
‭What? You're not gonna have any nonsense made-up food?
不  下午我们的互助会上还要称重的
No. Getting weighed at our meeting this afternoon.
你知道吗
You know what?
我也是
So am I.
我或许也不该吃了  该死的
I probably shouldn't eat, either. Damn.
互助会结束后  你想做什么
‭Hey, what do you want to do after the meeting?
我想去打迷你高尔夫
I was thinking miniature golf.
上一次  我不到20杆就打进了18洞
Last time I was like, 20 under going into the 18th,
但那个迷你风车捣了乱
but that little windmill owns my ass.
去不了  要看钢人队比赛
I can't. Steelers.
周日橄榄球之夜
Sunday Night Football. ‭
Sunday Night Football.
和谁一起
With who?
没别人  就我一个
Oh, no one. Just me.
好吧  我陪你一起看
All right. I'll watch with you.
不用了  谢谢  我自己看就行了
Oh, no. Thanks, but I'm good.
真的吗
Seriously?
你宁愿一个人看也不愿和我一起看
You'd rather watch by yourself than watch with me?
是的  那是我的个人爱好
Yeah. It's my thing.
我有这个习惯  你懂吧  个人爱好
I have a little ritual. You know? It's my thing.
好吧  你的个人爱好...
Well, your thing...
很悲哀啊
is sad.
我不觉得
Not to me.
好吧
Okay.
好吧  不如这样吧
Okay. How about this?
你可以看橄榄球
You can watch football...
你一个人看
all by yourself,
这很正常  但是要和我一起
which is totally normal, but with me.
托比
Toby. ‭
我就爱一个人看球
This is something that I do alone. Okay?
好吧
Sure.
太好了  谢谢你这么体贴
Great. Thank you for being so sweet.
你能帮我给这个加一碗糖吗
Can you bring, like, a bowl of sugar for this?
*如果你愿意给我*
*And if you give me*
*大麻*
*Weed*
*白葡萄酒*
*Whites*
*和红葡萄酒*
*And wine*
*给我一点暗示*
*And you show me a sign*
*那么我就*
*I'll be*
*我就愿意*
*Willin' to be*
*前行*
*Movin'.*
谢谢大家  钢人队加油
Thank you. Go, Steelers!
谢天谢地终于完了  能看比赛了吗
Thank God. Can we please watch the game now?
欢迎继续收看玫瑰碗
The Rose Bowl is back.
第十四届超级碗
这里座无虚席
Not an empty seat anywhere.
-借过一下  -唱得太棒了
- Excuse me. - That was amazing.
-真的吗  -真的
- Ah, yeah? Really? - ‭Yeah.
雪莉  米格尔
Oh! Shelly, Miguel.
他们到了
There they are.
-真抱歉我们迟到了  -没事的
- So sorry we're late. - It's okay.
-真是对不起  -都是因为孩子
- Oh, I'm so sorry. - Damn, kids, man.
我们正准备出门
We were just about to head out the door,
小宝宝就开始呕吐
and the baby decides to projective vomit
吐得小安迪满身都是
all over little Andy.
-也差点吐到我身上  -你猜安迪做了什么
- Almost got me, too. - So, what does Andy do?
你知道的  才四岁  体型像坦克一样
You know, four years old, built like a tank.
他扇了小宝宝一耳光
He slaps the baby.
就扇在脸上  啪的一声
Right across the face. Pow!
-不是吧  她还好吗  -她没事
- No! Is she okay? - Oh, she's fine. Yeah.
然后小宝宝就开始拼命尖叫
But then the baby's screaming bloody murder,
我也朝安迪喊
I'm screaming at Andy,
我就站在那儿  身上都是呕吐物  我就说
and me, standing there, covered in vomit, and I'm like,
安迪  她还是个婴儿
Andy, she is a baby.
你竟然扇了一个婴儿一巴掌
Like, you literally slapped a baby.
这真是帮了个倒忙  可想而知
Which really helped, as you can imagine.
没错  安迪也开始哭
Of course, then Andy starts crying,
-小宝宝哭  保姆也哭  -去喝点东西吧
- baby's crying, babysitter's crying. - We need drinks!
我们去喝点东西吧  一会就回来
We need drinks. We'll be right back.
好的
Okay.
跟我保证我们永远不要孩子
Promise me we are never having kids.
该喝点炮弹酒了
I think it's time for shots.
有人被扑到了
Somebody's down.
26号球员今天运气不好啊
26 is having a tough day.
我们的生活
第一季  第五集
公羊队上半场竟以13比10的比分
The first half, the Rams, surprisingly,
-领先匹兹堡钢人队  -真逊啊
- lead Pittsburgh 13 to 10. - Pathetic.
没有办法阻挡进攻
Can't stop the run.
布拉德肖真烂
Oh, and Bradshaw sucks!
不  布拉德肖会在下半场爆发的
Oh, no, Bradshaw's gonna have a huge second half, though.
对吗  亲爱的
Right, babe?
是的  下半场大爆发
Yeah. Big... big second half.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
很好
Mm. Fine.
好吧
Okay.
其实不好
Actually, no.
你之前那话是什么意思...
What did you mean before when, uh...
就是你说...
when you said...
"跟我保证我们永远不要孩子"
"Promise me we'll never have kids"?
我不该那样说的
Oh. I shouldn't have said that.
没错  但是你说了
Yeah, but... you did.
今天好像说了两次
Kind of said it twice today.
我不该说的
And I shouldn't have.
好吗
Okay?
对不起
Sorry.
你们知道我们该怎么做吗
You know what we need to be doing?
我们该多给弗兰科传球  对吧
We need to be feeding the ball to Franco more, right?
-这才...  -我们从来都不谈这事
-That's... -‭'Cause we-we never really talk about it.
我现在也不想谈这事
And I don't want to talk about it now, either.
我们总是说以后再说
We always say we're gonna talk about it in the future,
但现在就是谈的时候了  小贝
but it's the future now, Bec,
我想要孩子
and I want kids.
我们再去吧台拿几杯酒过来
You know what, we're gonna go grab another drink at the bar.
看看粉丝们的情况
and see how the fans--
现在我们来谈谈姜饼人和保罗·宏纳
Let's go to the Ginger Man and Paul Hornung. ‭
洛杉矶粉丝们肯定高兴坏了  保罗
L.A. Fans have to be happy, Paul.
睡觉时间是八点和九点
Bedtimes are at 8:00 and 9:00,
八点刷完牙  九点要上床
that's teeth brushed, in the bed. 8:00 and 9:00.
就是茴香酒就着安眠药喝下去
So one Sambuca to chase down the Ambien,
然后就熄灯  对吧
and then lights out, right?
玩笑开过头了
That's too far.
听着  放心吧
Okay, listen, relax.
我们今晚会乖乖待在家的
We're gonna have a nice, quiet evening at home. Okay?
孩子们玩自己的
The girls are gonna play.
我要熟记台词  背下来
I'm gonna memorize my lines and get off book.
声明一下  一般情况下
Look, we want to make it clear that we're not normally
我们是不会晚上单独留她们在家的
in the habit of leaving the girls overnight.
更别说交给俩没怎么和孩子们打过交道的人了
Let alone with two men who probably haven't been around kids that much.
其中一个还把自己的孩子遗弃在了消防局
One of them's best known for leaving a kid at a fire station.
天  请千万要照顾好我的孩子们
Oh, my God, please, take care of my babies.
还有  请别给我们打电话
And, please, don't call us.
不不  如果需要我们就打电话
No, no, call us if you need us.
最好别需要我们
But don't need us.
在你们走之前  还有一件事
Oh, one more thing, though, before you go.
苔丝就是
So, Tess was the, uh,
喜欢喝白葡萄酒  是吧
the white wine drinker, right?
然后安妮喜欢喝红酒  我可不想搞混了
Annie likes the red 'cause I don't get that wrong.
惹得她们不高兴
Piss them off.
还是有点过头了  我从你们的表情看出来了
It's still too far. I can tell by the way you...
玩笑是有点过头了
Yes. ‭It's a little too far.
-他太不正经了  -没关系的
- He plays too much. ‭- It's okay.
-没关系的  -太不正经了
- It's okay. - He plays too much.
如果有需要就给我们打电话
Hey, call us if you need anything.
别打电话
Don't call us.
我在控制饼干食用量方面有问题
So, I have, you know, this-this issue with-with cracker control,
我发现很有帮助的方法
so what I've been finding to be really helpful ‭
就是...
is if I...
把饼干从盒子里拿出来
take the portion out of the box
然后把饼干放在盘子上
and then I put the portion onto the plate
-把盒子  -递过去就行了
- and then I put the box - Just pass it.
放得远远的  然后我就知道我只能吃
away, and then I know how-how many crackers
多少块饼干了
I'm allowed to-to have.
递过去就行了
Just pass it.
多少块饼干
To h -- to have.
我知道了如果我只能吃十块饼干
So then I know that if-if I'm only allowed to have ten crackers,
我就只放十块饼干在盘子里
then I have the ten crackers on my plate,
这挺好的  但是同时
which is fine, but at the same time,
对于一些饼干来说
there are other crackers that I like than-than
我更喜欢吃另外的几种饼干
other crackers. So, I might not like
比如我更喜欢吃芝士饼干
saltine crackers as much as I like
而不是很喜欢苏打饼干
a Cheez-It type cracker,
你被邀请参加托比的"钢人队"派对
那么我对于芝士饼干
but so, what I'll do with the Cheez-It type cracker
触地得分  加油钢人队
我也许会多放几块在盘子里
is maybe put a little bit more on the plate,
但我还是会严格控制数量
but I'm still rationing,
所以如果是苏打饼干  我会放十块在盘子里
so if I have a saltine, then I might put ten on the plate,
如果是芝士饼干  就会放二十块
but there might be 20 if it's a Cheez-It. ‭
但我还是会把盒子拿开  所以
But I still put the box away. So, I-I mean
我觉得这也算是一种胜利吧
I-I think that's -- that's a win.
她总是出差
She was always away on business.
我已经习惯孤独了  但是这...
So, I was used to being alone but this, you know, this...
这是另外一种孤独
but this was a different kind of alone.
她总是出差  我已经习惯了...
She was always away on business, so I was used to being...
但是  我...
but... so, I was...
她总是出差  我已经习惯孤独了
She was always away on business, so I was used to being alone,
但是这是另外一种孤独
but this was a different kind of alone.
这是另外一种孤独
You know? This-this is a different kind of...
你们不是在看电影吗
I thought you two were watching a movie.
我们想举办一场芭比娃娃时装秀
We want to have a Barbie fashion show.
不错呀  听上去很好玩
Oh, cool. That sounds fun.
去玩芭比娃娃时装秀吧
So, go play Barbie fashion show.
我们想让你当明星评委
We need you to be the celebrity judge.
这样
Right.
但是我不行
Uh, the thing is I can't,
因为明天要排练了
because I got this rehearsal tomorrow
而且我很想脱稿  所以...
and I really want to be off book, so...
"脱稿"是什么意思
What does "Off book" mean?
脱稿  脱稿的意思就是
Off book. Off book means, uh,
意思就是我背下了台词
means that I know my lines.
让爷爷当评委好了
Have Grandpa be the judge.
爷爷不是明星呀
Grandpa's not a celebrity.
是呀
Yeah.
她们的逻辑挺合理的
Their logic seems sound.
谢谢你了
Thank you.
这样吧  你们想不想
Okay. Um... tell you what? You want to,
你们想帮帮我吗  想不想
you want to help me? You want to,
想不想和我一起念台词
you want to read the play with me?
-好呀  -来吧来吧
- Okay. - ‭Yeah. Oh, come on.
-可以  -来吧来吧
- Okay. ‭- Yeah, let's do that.
来吧  来这边  威廉
Come on, over here. William,
-快来吧  -我可不是什么演员
- let's do it. - I'm not much of an actor.
这没关系
Oh, doesn't matter.
我只需要有人来念一下台词
I just need to get the lines down, so...
苔丝  从你开始
All right, Tess, we'll start with you.
你演杰西卡  大卫的妻子
Uh, you're gonna be Jessica, David's wife.
凭什么她可以演杰西卡
Why does she get to be Jessica?
因为你演格雷西
Oh, because you're Gracie, okay?
格雷西是杰西卡的妈妈  很酷
Gracie's Jessica's mom, which is kind of cool.
你可以对你姐姐颐指气使了
It means you get to boss your sister around.
怎么样  不错吧
How's that sound?
威廉  有很多问题
So. William, multiple questions.
第一个问题  老实说
First one, I'm not gonna lie to you,
-这问题有点微妙  -问吧
- it's a little delicate. - ‭Go ahead.
你识字吗
Do you know how to read?
对  我识字
Yes, I can read.
我知道  我是跟你开玩笑呢
I knew it. I was joking.
你当然识字了
Of course you know how to read.
和你开玩笑呢
Trying to be funny. Okay.
你能不能念一下布拉德的台词
So if you could please read the role of Brad.
好极了  你去哪儿
Terrific, okay. Whoa, where we going?
我要尿尿
I have to pee.
我也要去尿尿
Oh, I kind of do, too.
你们怎么...我的天
What are you... Oh, good God.
这才像样嘛
Now, this is what I'm talking about.
宝贝  这样安排
Okay, babe, here's the plan.
先做爱
Sex first.
马上就做
Right away.
震耳欲聋  翻云覆雨
Loud, adult,
不用顾忌隔壁有小孩的那种
no kids in the next room sex.
而且不用来什么性爱马拉松
And it doesn't have to be marathon sex.
我们只要搞定这活
We just need to get the job done.
还有在看完《购房人》之前
And under no circumstances are we allowed
谁都不准先睡着
to fall asleep afterwards watching House Hunters.
不能整晚都浪费在睡觉上  对吧
Don't want to miss the whole night sleeping. Right?
我们要边淋浴边做
We'll do it in the shower.
超爽
That's good.
可别在豪华淋浴间睡着了
Won't fall asleep in the big fancy shower.
在此之前我们得先叫客房服务
And we'll order room service before.
这样一来  在结束成人式淋浴放荡性爱后
That way we will finish our loud adult shower sex
正好来客房服务  我们就可以穿着浴袍
just as room service arrives and we will slip on robes
啃汉堡  不  慢着  意大利面
and eat burgers... No, wait-- spaghetti.
不  我还是喜欢汉堡
No, I like burgers better.
我们要躺在床上啃汉堡
We will eat burgers in bed.
现在关键的问题是
Oh. Now, the big question is...
看什么付费节目好呢
what to order on pay-per-view.
我真希望他们这有
Oh, I already hope they, uh,
休·格兰特和梅丽尔·斯特里普的电影
I hope they have that Huge Grant-Meryl Streep movie that
这名字听着像个女黑人  瞧瞧
sounds like a black lady. Come on.
《跑调天后》
Florence Foster Jenkins.
宝贝  他们这有《跑调天后》
Baby, they already got Florence Foster Jenkins.
我月经迟了
I'm late.
迟了一周半  兰德尔
I'm a week and a half late, Randall,
我感觉糟透了
and I feel like crap.
昨天一整天我都在嚼冰
And I was chewing on ice all day yesterday
看到披萨的时候我差点吐了
and I almost threw up when I looked at pizza
而且我办不到自己一个人去药店
and I cannot bring myself to go to the drugstore
买验孕棒
and get a pregnancy test.
我彻底慌了  宝贝
I'm bugging out, baby.
你得让我冷静下来
I need you to talk me down.
-你好吗  -很好
- Hey, how are you? ‭- Hey, good.
进来吧  我们有胡萝卜  芹菜
Come on in. We got carrots, celery,
西兰花  无蘸酱  不用客气
broccoli, no dip. You're welcome.
谢谢  真不错
Thank you, that's so nice.
凯特  这是我好朋友  舒特
Oh, and, uh, Kate, this is my good friend, Shooter.
舒特  这是凯特
Shooter, Kate.
很高兴认识你  凯特
Nice to finally meet you, Kate.
我也是
Hi. Nice to meet you, too.
好消息  你们都喜欢体育  所以...
Great news. You both love sports, so...
体育派对
sports party.
你怎么看  杰克
So, what do you think, Jack?
比赛马上就要进入第四节了
Looking like it's gonna come down to the fourth quarter.
你想现在谈吗  好吧  我们来谈
You want to do this now? Okay. Let's do it.
那么
So...
我对你来说还不够
I am not enough for you.
你有我还不够吗  杰克
Am I not enough for you, Jack?
-撤回吧台吗  -好的
- Okay, back to the bar? - Yep.
我从没这么说  我是说
I never said that. I just meant
这个问题我们总归是要谈的
we need to have this conversation at some point.
可你非要现在谈  在这青蛙酒吧
Okay. And you want to do that right now, at Froggy's
-超级碗直播的时候  -是啊
- during the Super Bowl? - Yes,
麻烦再大声点  别让我们错过你们的好戏
please don't make us miss a second of your drama.
你能别管闲事吗
Could you butt out?
宝贝  我们一直拿这事开玩笑
Babe, we joke about it.
我们看见别人带着孩子  就说
We see people with kids and go,
"谢天谢地  幸亏不是咱俩"
"Oh, thank God that's not us."
我们拿它开玩笑  不是吗
We joke about it. Right?
难道我理解错了吗
Did I not get the joke?
我不是...
I'm not...
宝贝  你是对的
Babe, you're right.
你是对的
You are right.
就我成长的家庭而言
And coming from the family that-that I did,
我从没想过要自己的孩子
I definitely never saw myself having kids.
-好的  -但后来我遇见了你
- Okay. ‭- But then I met you.
而且  我们在一起很快乐
And, you know, we're j... we're great together
我喜欢我们的生活
and I love our life.
但随着年龄增长  我越发觉得...
But the older we get, the more I think that...
我越发觉得应该有超越你我两人
the more I think there's got to be something bigger
更有意义的事
than just me and you.
真是谢谢你把我加入
Well, thank you very much for involving me
你无形的巨大变化中  超巨大
in this huge invisible change of yours. Huge.
因为在你遇见我  直到娶了我
Because you knew when you met me and married me
就知道我不是那种
that I did not want to be one of those women
把成为母亲作为人生唯一目标的女人
whose sole purpose in life was to be a mother.
如果那是你想要的  你当初就该娶我妈
If that's what you wanted, you should have married my mom.
我更希望是你妹妹
I was thinking more your sister.
我估计也是
Oh. You probably were.
我只是...这玩笑不好笑
I'm... it's a bad joke.
我还没准备好  杰克
I'm not there yet, Jack.
我还没准备好
I'm not there yet.
-我才29  -快30了
- I am only 29. - ‭Almost 30.
我知道自己几岁
I know how old I am!
席德和南茜  你俩能出去吵吗
Hey, Sid and Nancy, will you two take it outside?
《席德与南茜》1986年电影
传奇摇滚乐队吉他手席德与其女友南茜相爱相杀
-你能闭嘴不  -管好你自己的事
- Could you just shut up for a second? - Mind your business.
大伙都被你们吵得听不见球赛了
None of us can hear the game over your mouth.
你得学学礼貌了  老兄
You got to learn some manners, pal.
你得管好你的女人
You need to control your woman.
你说话小心点
You need to watch your mouth.
杰克  坐下
Jack, sit down.
回来  没必要吵
Come here. It's not worth it.
杰克  坐下  求你了
Jack, sit down, please.
杰克
Jack.
-天啊  杰克  -杰克  杰克
- God, Jack. - ‭Jack! Jack.
不  不  不  不
No! No, no, no, no.
是啊
Yeah,
我们真应该要孩子
we should really be having kids.
药店
你不想说点什么吗
Aren't you gonna say anything?
好吧  这怎么可能
Uh, yeah. Like, how?
-你每天都有按时吃药吧  -没错
- You take the pill every day like clockwork, right? - Yeah.
还是我又不小心把哪粒药丢进我奶昔里了
What, did I accidentally drop one in my shake or something?
不  我...
No. I...
我上个月换了药
I mean, I changed medications last month
可能出现了短暂的排卵期
and there might have been, like, a brief window.
短暂的排卵期
A brief window?
抱歉
Sorry.
短暂的排卵期  贝丝
A brief window, Beth?
难道你没想过该跟你的丈夫
Did it not occur to you that that might be something
提这件事吗
you want to run by your husband?
我又不知道会出问题
Well, I didn't know it was gonna be a problem.
查尔斯顿泡汤了
Well, there goes Charleston.
抱歉  你说什么
Okay, I'm sorry, what?
十年之后  等女儿们都去上大学了
Ten years from now, when the girls are both off at college,
我想我们可以早些退休移居查尔斯顿
I thought that we would take an early retirement in Charleston.
不好意思  兰德尔
Oh, forgive me, Randall,
可你到底在说什么鬼
but what in the holy hell are you talking about?
你什么时候开始想搬去查尔斯顿了
Since when do you want to move to Charleston?
我看到电视上的介绍
I saw something about it on CNN.
在那可以享受高质量生活  高档餐厅
Like, they got a great quality of life, good restaurants.
工作闲暇时  我也会上网搜搜
Sometimes at work, I look up places on Zillow.
好吧  我真的非常抱歉
Oh, okay. Well, I'm so sorry that
让你最高机密的查尔斯顿之梦破碎了  宝贝
I'm screwing with your super top secret Charleston dream, honey.
我的问题和你的相比不值一提
No, my issues are nothing compared to yours.
-没人这么说  -等等  等等
- Nobody's saying that. - Wait,wait, wait, wait, wait,
来猜个谜语
here's a riddle--
是谁做好一切准备重返工作岗位
who has two hands and was about to go back to work full-time
这或许...或许能让她找回从前的自己
and maybe, maybe... start to remember who she was?
好吗
Yeah?
可现在她只能把时间花在
But now will have to split her time between
换尿布台和家庭办公室了
a diaper station and a home office?
这女人  就在此
This girl, right here.
-是两根拇指  -什么
- It's two thumbs. - ‭What?
你姿势不对
You're doing it wrong.
你应该说"谁用两根拇指
You're supposed to say what has two thumbs and is
-把时间花在..."  -闭嘴
- gonna be splitting time betw..." - ‭Shut up.
好的  都听你的  贝丝
Okay, that's real nice, Beth.
-一条口香糖  -麻烦了
- Also, some Altoids. - ‭Please.
瞧瞧这画面
Look at that picture.
太清晰了
That is a vivid picture.
就像在现场看一样
I feel like I'm at the game.
跑过了赛场
Over across the field, here.
这电视是挺不错
Yeah. It's a really nice TV...
这是什么屏
What is this?
等离子
Plasma?
LED
LED?
我不太清楚  但...
You know, I'm really not sure, but...
托比
Hey, Toby!
什么事
Yeah?
-你们爱吃凉薯吗  -等离子还是LED
- Uh, do you guys like jicama? - ‭Plasma or LED?
我...
I...
不知道
have no idea.
-凯特  凉薯  -什么
- Kate? Jicama? ‭- What?
这是蔬菜还是水果
Is that a vegetable or a fruit?
能挪个地儿吗  小托
Can... can you actually just move, Tob?
好好好
Oh! Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Yep.
外接手到位了
The receiver's all set.
往右  本看着中间
To the right, Ben looks straight over the middle,
跑向达阵区
and going for the end zone!
舒特  跟凯特说说
Shooter, uh, tell Kate
那次我们误打误撞
about that time we accidentally
去听了艾希莉·辛普森演唱会的事
went to an Ashlee Simpson concert.
真得跟你说说
Uh, you got to hear this.
-我们当时是想...  -不好意思
- So, we were trying to... - I'm sorry.
托比  你按了暂停
Toby, you paused the TV.
就这样暂停了
It's like, paused.
是啊  就一会儿  你听他说
Yeah, just for a second. Listen to this.
真的值得一听
No, this is a great story.
不  好吧
No. O-Okay,
其实没什么
I know it's not a big deal, really,
只不过我比较喜欢
but I kind of like to watch sports
看球赛直播
as they happen live.
可能只有我这样吧
Probably just me, right?
-我不知道  -好  好  我们继续
- I don't know. - Okay. Okay. Here we go.
-像是在等...  -我们延时了
- ...tends to wait... - Now we're behind the game!
快进
Fast forward it!
触地得分
Touch down!
海沃德全程自己一个人从左侧突围...
And Heyward made it all alone down the left side...
厉害  你喜欢的球队是吧
That's great. That's your team, right?
我心中的梦之队
That's my fantasy team.
-那是什么  -跟你们说
- What's that? - ‭You know what,
抱歉打断一下
I'm so sorry to interrupt,
我不太舒服
I'm actually not feeling good.
我得先走了
I'm gonna go ahead and go.
不会吧
Oh, no!
真的要走了吗
Are you sure?
凯特  留下吧
No, Kate, stay.
舒特
Shooter...
-很高兴见到你  -很高兴见到你
- It was really nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you.
-什么  等等  -认真的
- What... wait, wait, wait. - Seriously,
-谢谢你做了凉薯  -什么
- thank you for the jicama. - ‭What...
晚点再聊
I'll talk to you later.
怎么了
What is happening?
你得放下她  大卫
You have to let her go, David.
这样太不理智了
This is crazy, man.
她走了  不会再回来了
She's gone and she's never coming back.
你之前真的没演过戏吗
You really never acted before?
没
Nope.
丝绸一般的嗓音
Voice like silk.
我怎么放得下  大卫
How am I supposed to move on, David?
不对  我是大卫
No. I'm David.
我怎么放得下  布拉德
How am I supposed to move on, Brad?
你凭什么劝我放下
And who made you the expert of moving on?
你凭什么说我
Or the expert of anything for that matter?
你打算就这么演吗
Is that how you're gonna do it?
不是
No.
那就好
Good.
到你了
It's your line.
苔丝  亲爱的  下一句是你了
Tess, honey, you have the next line.
集中注意力
Pay attention.
我...我不希望你放下
‭I-I'd rather you not move on. I'm--
我...我显然没这打算
I'm obv-- I'm obviously not planning to.
不好
It's not good.
没你想的那么容易是吧
Not as easy as it looks, is it?
-是的  -是吧  好
- No. - ‭No. Okay.
她在那  你看见她了吗
There she is! Do you see her?
谁  大卫吗  我看到谁了
Who, David? Did I see who?
她啊  她就在那
Her! She's right there.
在她死后
And ever since she died,
她的鬼魂就一直跟着我
her ghost has been haunting me.
等等
Hold up.
怎么了  亲爱的
What's the matter, sweetheart?
这是个什么故事
What's happening in this story?
你没懂这个故事吗
You're not following the story?
你懂了吗
Do you follow it?
当然  我当然懂
Of course. Yes, of course I follow it.
她死了是吧
She died, right?
她死了
She's dead.
但她的鬼魂一直阴魂不散
But she keeps coming back as a ghost.
所以你死后就会变成鬼吗
So when you die you become a ghost?
不会
No.
不不不  亲爱的  鬼都是假的
No, no, no, no, no. No. Sweetheart, ghosts aren't real.
那你死了之后会发生什么
So what happens when you die?
你死了之后会发生什么
What happens when you die?
你就死了
Uh, is... you die.
永远吗
Forever?
是的  也可能不是
Sure... or not.
我不知道  亲爱的  是这样的
I don't know. Honey, here's the thing, you know,
你想不想要鬼  我可以...
do we want ghosts or do we not want ghosts? Because I can...
爷爷因为生病了总吃药
Grandpa takes pills because he's sick,
爷爷会死吗
is Grandpa gonna die?
为什么要问我
Why are you asking me this?
会吧  会
Yes? Yes.
快了吗
Soon?
跟你们说
Well, you know, I mean,
我是你的话就不会投入太多感情...
I wouldn't get too attached if I were you, so...
不  不不不
No! No, no, no.
我不是这个意思  我话是这么说
That's not what I meant. Look, I-I mean, I meant it,
但我只是想活跃气氛  是个笑话  好吗
but I was trying to be fun... It was a joke, okay?
死亡是一件很自然的事
Here's the thing about death, is that it's natural.
是自然规律  我也会死  明白吗
It's just natural. I'm gonna die, okay?
你们俩  你们也会死
You two? You're gonna die.
爸爸妈妈也会死
Mommy and Daddy are gonna die.
-爸爸妈妈会死吗  -不是...
- Mommy and Daddy are gonna die? - No. Uh...
听着...我的天  时间不早了
Look, uh, oh, my gosh, Wil... it is getting late.
要睡觉了  孩子们
It's bedtime, girls.
-来吧  孩子们  -对的
- Come on, girls. - Yep.
睡觉了  睡个好觉
Time to go to bed. Uh, sleep tight.
谢谢你们帮我
Thanks for all the help.
别忘了刷牙
Don't forget to brush your teeth.
你们什么时候决定要小孩的
Wh-when did you guys know you wanted kids?
大概是在她第一次怀孕的四个月后
Uh, about, uh, four months into her first pregnancy.
丽贝卡觉得如果我们有了小孩
Rebecca thinks that if we have kids,
我们的生活就完了
our lives are gonna be over.
她说得对  哥们
She's right, pal. Yeah.
她说得对
She's totally right.
那时你们可以跟生活说再见了
You can kiss this life good-bye.
如果她不想要小孩呢
What if she doesn't want kids?
这真的有那么重要  不惜闹僵吗
Is that really like a, like a deal-breaker?
我去找雪莉
I got to go find Shelly.
被人给截球了
That over the wrong shoulder.
这是有史以来最精彩的一次接球
That's one of the great catches you'll ever see.
近67米
73 yards.
玫瑰碗最厉害的球队
And the terrible towels will come out
就要诞生了
throughout the Rose Bowl.
谁是最佳球队已毋庸置疑
Not much doubt about the best team.
青蛙酒吧
刚刚获悉  由体育杂志及其投票团
Just been informed that the MVP for this contest
选举的本次比赛
as picked by Sport Magazine
最佳球员是特里·布拉德肖
and their panel of voters is Terry Bradshaw.
出口
这可不是我今晚的计划
This isn't the night I had planned.
我知道
I know.
要看吗
Shall we look?
等等  我们...
Wait. Just, um, let's... let's...
我们再等三十秒吧
let's give it like, 30 more seconds.
好
Okay.
你仍然可以接更多工作
You'll still be able to work more.
我可以减少工作量
I can work less.
我们可以找个保姆
We'll get a nanny.
或者"靓男保姆"
Or a manny.
天啊  不要
God, no.
如果你还想去
You know, if you still want
-什么度假屋  你可以...  -不要了
- that vacation house, you can... - ‭I don't.
太麻烦了
It's too much trouble.
要担心飓风
Worrying about hurricanes
还要担心会不会有小孩闯进来
and whether or not it gets broken into by some kids
用来...  谁知道干嘛呢
using it for their who knows what?
南卡罗莱纳州的小混混们
Damn South Carolina punk-ass kids.
有个儿子应该不会太糟
You know, a son wouldn't totally suck.
我们生的孩子都很棒
We do make good kids.
是啊  都很棒
That we do, that we do.
姑娘们会喜欢的
The girls will love it.
她们会乐疯的
Oh, they'll go nuts.
是谁有两根拇指
What has two thumbs
还如此地深爱着自己的妻子
and loves his wife so much it hurts?
说"两根拇指"确实好一些
Oh, it does work better with two thumbs.
不  我还是喜欢你的方式
Nah. I like the way you do it.
这样啊...  那我喜欢你的表情
Mm. Well... I like your face.
要看看吗
Shall we do this?
刚才的交流脱离控制了  对吧
Well, that conversation went sideways, didn't it?
兰德尔知道了一定会揍我的
Randall's gonna punch me for that conversation.
我得去和孩子们谈谈
I got to go talk to the girls.
和孩子们谈谈...  我应该说什么呢
Go talk to the girls-- what am I gonna say?
我显然不是那个
You know, I am clearly not the man
能够和她们讨论
that needs to be talking to them
这些生死之类的复杂话题的人
about the intricacies of life and death.
这实在...
It's...
你总是这样
You do that a lot.
我总是怎么样
I do what a lot?
怀疑自己
Doubt yourself.
你演得很好  凯文
You were very good, Kevin.
在那个剧里
On that show.
你看了《靓男保姆》吗
You watched The Manny?
来这里之前  有台旧电视机
Before I came here, I had one old television,
只有三个台能看
got three channels.
我非常喜欢那个节目
I really liked that program.
我当时想  这人真有才啊
And I remember thinking, he's very talented.
我喜欢你失去宝宝的那集
I liked the one where you lose the baby.
天啊
Oh, geez.
《男保姆发火》
"Manny on Fire."
是啊  那集...
Yeah, you know. That was a...
那集非常精彩
That was a strong episode.
-没错  -是啊
- Yeah. ‭- Yeah, yeah.
我真不该退出那部剧
I never should have left that show.
我...
I've...
我不该来这里的  毫无疑问
I never should have come here, that's for sure.
过来照顾侄女  演什么戏剧...
Being an uncle, right, doing theater...
我...
I... I...
我根本不是演戏剧的料
I'm not cut out for theater.
你又开始了
And there you go again.
好吧  你说起来容易啊  对吧
Well, yeah, I mean, that's easy for you to say, right?
你就是皮克斯动画片里那只聪明的猫头鹰
You're the wise owl in a Pixar film.
而我是那只愚蠢的拉布拉多犬
I'm the dopey Labrador.
我是离死不远的戒了毒的瘾君子
I'm a dying recovering addict.
-随你说了  -聪明的猫头鹰说了
- Yeah, whatever. - ‭Yeah, well, people love Labradors.
人们都喜欢拉布拉多
Said the wise owl.
你知道是怎么回事吗
You want to know what it is?
在这部戏里
It's this play, right?
和我一起工作的那些人
I mean, these people that I'm working with,
他们简直比我聪明一个级别
wow, they're like next level smart.
我是说  他们太优秀了
I mean, uh, they're brilliant.
他们看我的眼神就好像  我是个笑话
And then they look at me like I'm a joke, right?
搞得我都怀疑自己是个笑话
Which makes me start to think that I am a joke,
然后我就开始失去方向
and then I start spinning.
我甚至再也搞不清这部戏在讲什么
I don't even know what the play's about anymore.
凯文  你最初读剧本时觉得是讲什么的
Kevin, what did you think it was about when you first read it?
这不重...  这不重要  这实在...
You know, it doesn't ma-- it doesn't matter, it's...
你想说这太傻了
You're just gonna think it's stupid.
愚蠢的拉布拉多说的
Said the dopey Labrador.
青蛙酒吧
我们胜利了
We did it!
如果要在你和生孩子之间做选择  我选你
If it's between you and having kids, you win.
每次如此
Every time.
毫无疑问
No question.
我爸爸
My father,
他爱橄榄球胜过一切
he loved football more than anything.
大多时候  他根本
Most of the time, he-he pretty much
就不怎么理我
didn't want anything to do with me.
可是...  如果他在看球赛
But... if he was watching football,
他会让我坐好
he let me sit
和他一起看球赛
and watch the game with him.
每当我坐在地板上时
As long as I'd sit on the floor
我几乎一言不发
and I didn't talk too much.
我总是在想  以后我有了孩子
I always imagined that when I had kids
我也会和他们一起看球赛
that I'd watch the games with them, too.
但是我会让他们说话
Except I-I'd let them talk...
想说多大声都行
as loud as they wanted.
我不知道自己是怎么了
I don't know what's wrong with me.
你一点问题也没有  小贝
God, there's nothing wrong with you, Bec.
和我同龄的朋友都有孩子了
All of my friends my age have kids.
每一个都有了
Every single one of them.
可是...
And...
也许是因为我还在青蛙酒吧唱歌
maybe it's 'cause I'm still singing at Froggy's
而且我觉得我还不够格做父母
and I'm not as far along as I thought I would be.
我不知道
I don't know.
事实就是  每当我闭上眼
'Cause the truth is, when I close my eyes
想象我们的未来...
and I think about our future...
我看见我们在带孩子  杰克
I see us with kids, Jack.
是啊
Yeah.
我就是...
I just...
我喜欢我们的生活
I love our life.
就喜欢现在的生活
I love it right now.
我很怕会有改变
And I'm so scared of changing it.
我不会去改变我们的生活
I don't want to change it.
好吗  我无法容忍我们之间有任何改变
Okay? I'm not gonna stand for anything changing between us.
我们之间的感情  就你和我
Okay? What we have together, you and me.
什么都不会改变
Nothing.
我很抱歉整天给你压力
Look, I'm sorry about pressuring you all day.
我只是...
I just...
我只想要你
I just want you.
钢人队赢了超级杯
The Steelers won the Super Bowl.
Steelers won the Super Bowl.
布拉德肖赢得了最佳球员奖
Bradshaw won MVP.
我的天[男人]
My man.
是
Yes.
我是
I am.
你是
You are.
好
‭Okay.
那么
So, uh...
你今天怎么回事
what was all that about today?
我说了  我想自己看比赛
I told you I wanted to watch the game by myself.
那你为什么同意过来
Then why did you agree to come over?
不知道
I don't know.
因为我不想
'Cause I didn't want to...
看起来像个怪咖
seem like a weirdo.
好  我现在知道了
Okay. So, now I know.
不能在橄榄球赛季的周末约你
No hanging out on Sundays during football season.
-知道了  -但重点不只是橄榄球
- I got it. ‭- But it's not just about football.
好吧  那重点是什么
Okay. What's it about then?
从小到大
Okay. So, growing up,
我总和我爸一起看匹兹堡钢人队的比赛
I used to watch the Steelers with my dad.
每个周末
Right? Every single Sunday,
直到我长大了
until I grew up and...
搬来这里  就没了这个习惯
I moved out here and I just got out of the habit.
直到2006年  美国橄榄球联盟冠军赛
It wasn't until the 2006 AFC Championship
他们跟丹佛野马队比赛  记得吗
when they played the Broncos. Do you remember?
不记得
No.
好吧  总之
Okay. Anyway,
我想和我爸一起看比赛
I wanted to watch 'em with my dad.
我看了  他们赢了
And I did. And they won.
然后他们赢了超级碗
And then they won the Super Bowl.
我就是...
And I just...
这就是我现在的习惯
It's just-just what I do now.
我看匹兹堡钢人队的比赛...
I watch the Steelers, and...
我和我爸一起看
I watch 'em with my dad.
他听起来是个不错的人
He sounds like a cool guy.
有时间介绍一下我认识吧
I'd like to meet him sometime.
好
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
好
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
Um... ‭All right.
我知道这有点瘆人
And I know it's gonna be a little creepy.
这是你爸吗
This is your dad?
杰克
Jack.
我知道这听起来很扯很逊
I know it sounds crazy and lame,
但我们家很重视橄榄球  特别重视
but football is a really big part of my family. Like, really big.
如果不是因为橄榄球  我都不会出生
Like, I wouldn't even be here if it wasn't for football.
我妈是超级碗比赛时  在卫生间怀上了我
I was conceived in a bathroom during the Super Bowl.
抱歉我之前态度不好
Sorry if I was a jerk before.
你们真不打算原谅我吗
You're really not gonna forgive me?
好吧
Okay.
那如果我告诉你们
What if I told you a-a secret
一个我从没跟人说过的秘密呢
that I've never shared with anyone before?
说说看吧
We're listening.
好  行
Okay. All right.
但你们得保证不告诉别人
But you got to promise not to tell anyone though, okay?
我要说的事很私密
This is a very private thing that I'm sharing with you.
是你和黛米·洛瓦托[歌手]交往的事吗
Is this about you dating Demi Lovato?
因为大家都知道这事
Because everyone knows.
不是  不是黛米·洛瓦托的事
No. You know what, it's not about Demi Lovato,
而且我跟她只是普通朋友  我...
and we were just friends. I just...
我有时候会画画
Sometimes I... paint.
谁都不知道这事  你凯特姑姑也不知道
Now, no one knows this, not even your Aunt Kate,
我拿到剧本时
but... when I get a script,
第一件事就是把自己的感觉画出来
the first thing I do is just sort of paint the way it makes me feel.
我第一次读了那个剧本后  就画了这幅画
I painted this after I read that play for the first time.
给
So...
我想我以前吓过你们
I think I scared you before.
讲什么鬼故事啊  死亡啊
Um, all that talk of ghosts and dying.
所有大人读过的故事
All that adult stuff we were reading about.
一些成让人困惑的大人事情
That's some pretty confusing adult stuff.
所以
So, uh, you know,
我以为我过来给你们看我的画
I thought I would come up here, show you my painting,
说一下我演那部戏的主题
tell you what I think my play is about.
因为我在想
Because I was thinking, um,
这会让我们都好受些
that it might make us all feel a little bit better.
但你们不能笑我  好吗
But you got to promise not to make fun of me, okay?
那么
So, um...
我画了这幅是因为我觉得这部剧的主旨是生活
Yeah, I painted this because I felt like the play was about life, you know?
生活充满了色彩
And life is full of color.
每个人一路走来
And we each get to come along
为生活带来了自己的颜色
and we add our own color to the painting.
尽管这幅画不是什么神作
You know? And even though it's not very big, the painting,
你得琢磨出让线条持续下午
you sort of have to figure that it goes on forever,
每个方向都无限延伸下去
you know, in each direction. So, like, to infinity, you know?
因为这就是生活  对吧
'Cause that's kind of like life, right?
仔细想想  其实很不可思议
And it's really crazy, if you think about it, isn't it,
一百年前
that, a hundred years ago,
一个我素未谋面的人带着行李箱来到这个国家
some guy that I never met came to this country with a suitcase.
他有一个儿子
He has a son,
儿子又有儿子
who has a son,
儿子的儿子又有儿子  就是我
who has me.
所以我一开始画的时候
So, at first, when I was painting,
我当时想  也学在这里
I was thinking, you know, maybe up here,
画中这里是这个人的起点
that was that guy's part of the painting and then, you know,
而我就在画的这里
down here, that's my part of the painting.
然后我开始思考  如果...
And then I started to think, well, what if...
如果我们都在画布上呢
we're all in the painting, everywhere?
三个小家伙
如果我们出生前  命运就已经被画好了呢
And-and what if we're in the painting before we're born?
三个小家伙
如果我们死后才会出现在画上呢
What if we're in it after we die?
三个小家伙
我们添加的这些颜色
And these colors that we keep adding,
如果都只是相互间颜色的叠加呢
what if they just keep getting added on top of one another,
直到最后我们都变成了同样的颜色呢
until eventually we're not even different colors anymore?
我们都只是一体的
We're just... one thing.
一幅画
One painting.
-幸运帽  -幸运帽
- Lucky cap. - ‭Lucky cap.
我爸不在我们身边了
I mean, my dad is not with us anymore.
他去世了  但他活在我们心里
He's not alive, but he's with us.
每天都活在我心里
He's with me every day.
未怀孕
一切都冥冥中自有安排
It all just sort of fits somehow.
即便你现在还不知道何时何地
And even if you don't understand how yet,
我们爱的人终将会离世
people will die in our lives, people that we love.
也许在未来
In the future.
也许在明天
Maybe tomorrow.
也许几年后
Maybe years from now.
其实挺美好的
I mean, it's kind of beautiful, right,
如果仔细想想  就算一个人死了
if you think about it, the fact that just because someone dies,
就算你见不到这些人
just because you can't see them
不能再和他们说话
or talk to them anymore,
不代表画中没有他们的位置
it doesn't mean they're not still in the painting.
我想也许这就是全部的意义所在
I think maybe that's the point of the whole thing.
没有死亡
There's no dying.
没有单独的你或我  或者他们
There's no you or me or them.
我们都是一体的
It's just us.
这幅...凌乱的
And this... sloppy...
狂野的  色彩缤纷的奇妙之画
wild, colorful, magical thing
没有起点  也没有终点
that has no beginning, it has no end...
这幅画
this right here...
这就是我们
I think it's us.